KUSHAGRA ACHARYA

Dhobighat-3, Lalitpur, Province 2, Nepal – +977-9860773808 – mail.kushagra.acharya@gmail.com
Portfolio | https://www.linkedin.com/in/kushagra.acharya@gmail.com

OUTLINE

Computer engineer with 4 years of experience as a Mobile Application Developer for Android as well as iOS platforms with Java, Kotlin, Swift, and Flutter. Also worked as a Software Engineer with backend technologies like NodeJS and NestJS to build APIs. Other experiences involve UI/UX development and project management.

EXPERIENCE

ZERO LOGIC SPACE Software Engineer

Chakupat, Lalitpur, Nepal 2022-Present

- Design various APIs with NestJS/NodeJS and PostgreSQL.
- Primarily developing native android applications for eCommerce organizations.
- Construct API as well as mobile applications for appointment management systems used in dental clinics.
- Plan and develop in-house products along with documentation development.
- Define CI/CD pipelines for android application testing and distribution.
- Design prototypes and UI for SaaS products.
- Worked with web application deployment and versioning with Nginx, git, and Linux server management.

Major Skills: Android, Tailwind, NextJS, NodeJS, NestJS, Project Management, SQL, Nginx, Git, Flutter, RestAPI

NEPAL PAYMENT SOLUTION (DIGIHUB) Native Mobile Application Engineer

Hattisar, Kathmandu, Nepal 2020-2022

- Developed fintech mobile applications such as digital wallets using various architectures for Android as well as iOS platforms with Java, Kotlin, and Swift
- Designed prototypes for mobile applications and guided engineering interns as well as design teams to create user-friendly applications.
- Strong knowledge of Dependency Injection (Dagger/Hilt), MVVM architecture, Activity Lifecycles, and Fragments management.
- Experience with the Dynamic Application Delivery module of GooglePlay.
- Developed applications with Data Binding and Live Data implementation.
- Worked with Room Database, Jetpack Navigation, Retrofit, and Coroutines.
- Experience with the latest Jetpack Compose design system.
- Developed Point of Sales android application using SDKs for thermal printing as well as biometrics.
- Deployed and maintained multiple applications in Google Play as well as AppStore with strong knowledge in analytics, Firebase implementation, and TestFlight.

- MVVM architecture setup knowledge in iOS applications with API handling using Alamofire.
- Knowledge of unit testing for both native android and iOS applications.
- Developed iOS apps with Core-Data wrapper for offline data persistence.
- Worked with SDKs like Google Maps, Facebook Analytics, and OCR APIs for mobile applications.
- Led team for successful mobile application delivery with knowledge of project management, JIRA, Agile, and Scrum with MVP development.

Major Skills: Android, iOS, Team Lead, Fintech, SIM Management, Scrum, Agile, GooglePlay, AppStore, Analytics, Push Notifications, MVVM, Git

PRABHU TECHNOLOGY Android Developer

Kamalpokhari, Kathmandu, Nepal 2019 –2020

- Practiced Android Development with Java/Kotlin.
- Development applications based on material designs.
- Experience with application architecture and reactive programming.
- Developed various standalone libraries as well as SDKs for third-party implementation
- Maintained and deployed applications with QR systems for scan and pay concepts.
- Worked in eCommerce application development and ticketing applications.

Major Skills: Material UI, XML, Android Layouts, Retrofit, SDK Development

EDUCATION

EVEREST ENGINEERING COLLEGE Bachelor of Computer Engineering

Sanepa, Lalitpur, Nepal 2014- 2019

- Affiliated with Pokhara University
- 3.15 GPA